Guide to the South African Apartheid Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-092
  - Subject files
    - Student protest, 1972, 1977, 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Television and radio, 1978, 1984, undated (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Transkei, [1974?], 1976-1977, undated (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - United States relations with South Africa
      - Aircraft, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 248)
      - Corporate Codes of Conduct, 1991, undated (Box 10, Folder 249)
      - Export Controls Bill, 1979-1983, n.d (Box 10, Folder 250)
      - Sanctions, [1970?], 1976, 1978, 1986-1991, undated (Box 10, Folder 251)
      - Testimonies pertaining to the South African Financial Sanctions Act, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 252)
      - Miscellaneous, 1970, 1976, 1978, 1981, 1986, 1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Writings [Clark, Catherine Bunmi, Letsoala, Essy], 1985 (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985, 1988-1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 255)
  - Photographs
    - General [scenes of daily life, sports events, monuments, people], 1987, 1990, undated (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - Amputees/maimed children, undated (Box 11, Folder 257)
    - "Apartheid: The Tyranny of Racism Made Law" [UN photographs, Johannesburg], 1982 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    - Children [groups of], undated (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - Damage to buildings, 1979-1985, undated (Box 11, Folder 260)
    - Damage to public infrastructures, 1983, 1985, undated (Box 11, Folder 261)
    - Massacre victims, 1976-1986, n.d (Box 11, Folder 262)
    - Military arsenal, undated (Box 11, Folder 263)
    - Military scenes [most likely Angola; primarily tanks], undated (Box 11, Folder 264)
    - People [groups of], undated (Box 11, Folder 265)
    - Protests, undated (Box 11, Folder 266)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976, 1983, undated (Box 11, Folder 267)
    - Weinberg, Eli [photographer: photographs from an exhibit prepared by the International Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa for the International Seminar on Publicity and Role of Mass Media in International Mobilization against Apartheid in cooperation with the government of the German Democratic Republic and the GDR Solidarity Committee, Berlin], 1981 August 31- September 2 (Box 12, Folder 268)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-074
  This addition consists of photocopies of card catalogues from the State Library in Pretoria of publications which were banned during apartheid.
  - State Library, Pretoria, South Africa
    - Card catalogue of banned publications [books unless otherwise noted]
      - 1968
        - A- Borneman (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Bot-Claussen (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Clayford-Denzer (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Des-Fontaine (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - For-Hegeler (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Heinrich-Keene (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Kelleam-McAlmon (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - McBain-Modern (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Modisane-Petrov (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Pettit-Ryland (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Saber-Sykes (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Tabrah-Werry (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - West-Z (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - A-Z [additional material] (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 1969
        - A-Z (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - 1971
        - Supplement II (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Supplement II [periodicals] (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 1972
        - Supplement I (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Supplement II (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Supplement II, III [periodicals] (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - 1973
        - Supplement I, III, IV (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - Supplement I-IV [periodicals] (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - 1974
        - Supplement I (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Supplement I [periodicals/ newspapers] (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-122
  This accession consists of printed material collected by the Washington Office on Africa. Items are listed alphabetically by name of organization or by subject matter. Whenever possible, original folder titles and arrangement were retained. There is a great overlap of subject material between the organization and subject files.
  - Non-governmental organizations
    - The Africa Fund, 1969, 1975-1981, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - African American Committee on the United Nations, 1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - African-American Labor Center (AALC), 1973-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - African Bibliographic Center, 1973-1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Africana Studies and Research Center, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - All Africa Press Service (APS), 1984-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - All African People's Revolutionary Party, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee (ADC), 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - American Committee on Africa (ACOA), 1969-1979, 1981-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - American Coordinating Committee for Equality in Sport and Society (ACCESS), 1979-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Americans Against Apartheid (AAA), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Amnesty International
      - 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1982-1983, 1988, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - 1982-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Labor News, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Artists United Against Apartheid, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Association of Concerned African Scholars (ACAS), 1981, 1985-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Association of West European Parliamentarians for Action Against Apartheid (AWEPAA), 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Blacks Against Nukes, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Center for Appeals for Freedom, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Center for Defense Information, 1979, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Center for Development Policy, 1978, 1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Centre for the Independence of Judges and Lawyers (CIJL), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Coalition for A Democratic Majority, 1976, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Committee for a Free South Africa (CFSA), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Committee to Support African Independence (CSAI), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Communist Party, USA, 1979, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Conservative Caucus Foundation, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Covert Action Publications, Inc., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Educators Against Apartheid, 1988-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - End Conscription Campaign (ECC), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - End Loans to South Africa (ELTSA), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Freedom House, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Fund for Open Information and Accountability, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Group Research [right wing], 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Human Rights Commission, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Institute for International Education, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Institute for Policy Studies, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - International Campaign Against Banking on Apartheid, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - International Committee Against Apartheid, Racism and Colonialism in Southern Africa (ICSA), 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - International Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1985, 1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - International Metalworkers' Federation, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - International University Exchange Fund (IUEF), 1978-1980, n.d (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Investor Responsibility Research Center (IRRC), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Joint Center for Political Studies (JCPS), 1976-1978, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1985-1986, 1991, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Liberation Support Movement, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Mondale/Ferraro Committee, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA), undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - New York Commission on Human Rights, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Patriotic Front (Zimbabwe), 1977-1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Shipping Research Bureau, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - South Africa Foundation
      - 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - 1980-1985, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - South African History Archive [ History in the Making ], 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Southern Africa Action Coalition, 1976-1980, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Southern Africa Committee [ Southern Africa ], 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Transafrica (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America [Economic Policy Committee], 1984 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - United Steelworkers of America (USWA), 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Washington Office on Africa (WOA)
      - General, 1968, 1973, 1980-1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Executive Branch [State Department positions on South Africa], 1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Subject Files
    - African American newspapers/publications, 1969-1972, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Anti-apartheid movements
      - Austria, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Denmark, 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - European Economic Community (EEC), 1979, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - France [primarily Apartheid Non! ], 1979-1986 (Box 4, Folder 68 - 69)
      - Germany, 1977-1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - Holland, 1978, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - Ireland, 1975-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Japan, 1984-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Netherlands, 1979-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - New Zealand, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Norway, 1979-1980, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Spain and South America, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Students, 1979-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Sweden, 1977-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 79 - 80)
      - United Kingdom, 1977-1979, 1982-1983, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Apartheid
      - General, 1976-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Analysis, 1987-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Bantustans
      - Bophuthatswana, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - KwaNatal, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 85)
      - KwaNdebele, [1985-1986] (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Blacks and Southern Africa Policy, 1976-1977, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Ciskei, 1983-1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Conference in Solidarity with the Liberation Struggles of the Peoples of Southern Africa, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Cuba, 1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Damaraland Tour (Washington D.C./Canada), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Divestment, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Economics, international, 1970, 1976-1983, undated
      - General (Box 6, Folder 93)
      - Minerals
        - A- P (Box 6, Folder 94)
        - T- Z (Box 6, Folder 95)
      - Oil (Box 6, Folder 96)
      - World Bank (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Economy, 1972-1989, undated
      - General (Box 6, Folder 98 - 99)
      - Boston SAFE (South Africa- Free Equity) Index (Box 6, Folder 100)
      - Energy/nuclear (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - Foreign investment
        - General (Box 7, Folder 102)
        - American Chamber of Commerce (Box 7, Folder 103)
        - Baldwin, Brooke (Box 7, Folder 104)
        - Sanctions (Box 7, Folder 105)
        - Transnational cooperations
          - A- F (Box 7, Folder 106)
          - G- M (Box 7, Folder 107)
          - N- Z (Box 7, Folder 108)
        - United States
          - Autos (Box 7, Folder 109)
          - Computers (Box 7, Folder 110)
          - Control data (Box 7, Folder 111)
          - Disinvestment/ divestment (Box 7, Folder 112)
          - Independent schools (Box 7, Folder 113)
          - List of US firms doing business in South Africa (Box 7, Folder 114)
          - Newmont Mining Corporation (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Mining
        - General (Box 7, Folder 116)
        - Diamonds (Box 7, Folder 117)
        - Gold (Box 7, Folder 118)
        - Uranium (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Oil/US Mobil (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - Pension funds (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - Sanctions/general (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Grassroots organizations
      - General, 1982-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - Students, 1977-1978, 1982-1985, undated (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Hunger, 1985-1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - International Monetary Fund (IMF)
      - 1981-1983 Apr (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - 1983 May-Dec, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Internewsletter Afrique, 1984, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Jackson, Jesse, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 129)
    - Kissinger, Henry A. [shuttle diplomacy], 1983 (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - Liberation, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Namibia
      - 1974, 1982-1985 (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - 1986-1988, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Oil embargo, 1977-1979, 1982-1987, undated (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Politics [white], 1972-1975, 1978, 1981-1988 (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - Propaganda, 1969, 1974-1985, 1989, undated
      - General (Box 9, Folder 136 - 138)
      - Blacks against sanctions (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Foreign agents list (Box 9, Folder 140)
      - South Africa Foundation (Box 9, Folder 141)
      - South African Embassy (Box 9, Folder 142)
      - United States
        - General (Box 9, Folder 143 - 144)
        - Kirkpatrick, Lockhart, Johnson and Hutchinson (Box 9, Folder 145)
        - Masimini, Ngondi [representative of Transkei] (Box 9, Folder 146)
        - Motsi, Jacob R. [agent for Bophuthatswana] (Box 9, Folder 147)
        - North American Precis Syndicate, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 148)
        - Pearson and Pipkin, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 149)
        - Plaia, Schaumberg and Dekieffer (Box 10, Folder 150)
        - Rubenstein, Wolfson and Co., Inc. (Box 10, Folder 151)
        - Smathers, Symington and Herlog (Box 10, Folder 152)
        - South African Tourist Corporation/tourism promotion (Box 10, Folder 153 - 154)
        - Spencer-Roberts and Associates (Box 10, Folder 155)
        - Sydney S. Baron Company, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 156)
      - Raids
        - Botswana, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 157)
        - Mozambique, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 158)
        - Zambia, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 159)
      - Refugees
        - General, 1980-1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 160)
        - Office of the United Nations High Commission for Refugees, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 161)
      - Repression, 1967, 1976-1978, 1983-1989, 1991, undated
        - General (Box 10, Folder 162 - 163)
        - American Sociological Association (ASA) [resolution on South Africa] (Box 10, Folder 164)
        - Analyses (Box 11, Folder 165)
        - Band Wagon (Box 11, Folder 166)
        - Detention
          - General (Box 11, Folder 167 - 170)
          - Children (Box 11, Folder 171)
          - Deaths (Box 11, Folder 172)
          - Hunger strike, 1989 January (Box 11, Folder 173)
          - Prison conditions/release of prisoners (Box 11, Folder 174)
          - Security laws [review of] (Box 11, Folder 175)
        - Executions (Box 11, Folder 176)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 177)
      - Rhodesia
        - General, 1965-1966, 1972-1978, undated (Box 12, Folder 178)
        - Internal settlement
          - Political developments/reactions, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 179)
          - UN action, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 180)
        - Rhodesian War
          - General, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 181)
          - Missionary killings, 1976-1978, undated (Box 12, Folder 182)
        - Sanctions
          - General, 1980-1987, 1991, n.d (Box 12, Folder 183)
          - State and local, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 184)
      - Smith, Damu [includes photographs], 1972, 1977, 1985, undated (Box 12, Folder 185)
      - South African sugar quota, 1967-1974, undated (Box 12, Folder 186)
      - Transkei, 1976-1978, 1988, undated (Box 12, Folder 187)
      - United Nations
        - Conferences
          - International Conference in Support of the Struggle of the Namibian People for Independence, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 188)
          - World Conference of Action Against Apartheid, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 189)
        - Development Programme, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 190)
        - General Assembly, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 191)
        - Resolutions Adopted by the United Nations General Assembly and Security Council on the Question of Apartheid, 1960-1980 (Box 13, Folder 192)
        - Special Committee Against Apartheid
          - 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 193)
          - 1984-1987 (Box 13, Folder 194)
        - US-UN action on apartheid, 1972-1976, 1981-1986 (Box 13, Folder 195)
      - United States
        - Aid to South Africa, 1979-1986, undated (Box 13, Folder 196)
        - Department of Justice, 1987-1990 (Box 13, Folder 197)
        - Foreign relations
          - Angola
            - 1969, 1971, 1975-1979 (Box 13, Folder 198)
            - 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 199)
            - 1982, 1986-1988, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 200)
          - Economic/foreign aid, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 201)
          - Human rights, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 202)
          - International terrorism, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 203)
          - Military, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 204)
          - Minerals, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 205)
          - Mozambique [includes Angola]
            - 1969, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 206)
            - 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 207)
            - 1980-1986, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 208)
          - Third World, 1979-1982 (Box 14, Folder 209)
          - USSR, 1978-1979, undated (Box 14, Folder 210)
        - Policy, Angola, 1983-1986, undated (Box 14, Folder 211)
        - Politics/government
          - General, [1981], 1982, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 212)
          - Arms Control and Foreign Policy Caucus, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 213)
          - Campaigns/Sullivan Principles, 1983-1989, undated (Box 14, Folder 214)
          - Congress
            - Ad Hoc Monitoring group on South Africa, 1980-1982, undated (Box 14, Folder 215)
            - Election, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 216)
            - House Resolution 1460, 1985, undated (Box 14, Folder 217)
            - Human Rights, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 218)
            - Members of Congress for Peace Through Law, 1976-1981 (Box 14, Folder 219)
            - Namibia, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 220)
            - Sanctions, 1986, undated (Box 15, Folder 221)
          - Congressional Black Caucus, 1972-1975 (Box 15, Folder 222)
          - Foreign aid, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 223)
        - Relations with South Africa [trade/investment], 1982-1984 (Box 15, Folder 224)
        - World Conference Against Apartheid, Racism and Colonialism in Southern Africa, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 225)
      - Zimbabwe
        - 1979-1982 (Box 15, Folder 226)
        - 1982, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 227)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-139
  This accession consists primarily of printed material arranged in broad subject areas.
  - Arts/entertainment/museums, 1968-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Education, 1982, 1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Government, 1962-1963, 1969, 1978-1979, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International relations, 1975-1978, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Labor/industry
    - 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1982-1989, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Prisoners [non-political; letter from Pollsmoor Prison near Cape Town], 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Prisoners [political]
    - Torture [report from Operation Real South Africa], 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Treason [report on Passtoors trail], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph album [primarily Johannesburg and Durban], [1970s] (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-142
  - Photographs
    - District Six, Cape Town [from exhibition by photographers David Robinson and Peter Rademeyer], 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Funeral of unidentified person [most likely in one of the "homelands"], before 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Swart, C. and H. F. Verwoerd [includes pages from hotel register from N. Transvaal with signatures of President Swart and Prime Minister Verwoerd], 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-144
  This accession consists of photocopies of court documents relating to the trial of Mewa Ramgobin and others on the charge of treason, in South Africa, 1985.
  - "The State vs. Ramgobin and 15 Others," case no. CC71/85 [original arrangement retained]
    - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 5)
    - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6 - 7)
- Additional Material, Accession 2002-M-066
  This accession consists of printed material pertaining to economic sanctions and disinvestment, focusing on the Shell Boycott Campaign.
  - International companies, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Shell Boycott Campaign, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-044
  This accession consists of alphabetically listed printed materials pertaining to political parties and civil society organization in South Africa during the apartheid regime.
  - The African Journalist [no. 80], 1990 April-May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Die Afrikaner- Volkswang [3 different issues], 1989 Apr, Mar, 1990 August (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Afrikanerland [photocopies of maps, proposed state boundaries and plans], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Azania Commando [supplement to Azania Combat, the official organ of the Azanian People's Liberation Army, the PAC military wing], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Letter from South Africa [a monthly viewpoint on South Africa, no. 3], 1990 Mar/April (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mbira NewsNotes [vol. IV, no. 1], 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Die Nationale Party (NP), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nuusbrief van die Boere- Vryheidsbeweging, 1989, 1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Omkeer [uncensored resistance magazine for white South African soldiers and draftees], 1979 Oct, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Patriot Review and Comment, 1990 August 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Pretoria News, 1990 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The South Africa Foundation News [vol. 13, no. 5], 1987 May (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - South Africa Foundation Review [vol. 16, no. 5], 1990 May (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Tragedy in Africa: a Warning and a Challenge" [publication of the Union of Democratic Control, London], undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vereniging van Oranjeworkers, 1989 Jan/Feb, 1990 Apr, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Witness to Apartheid" [a teaching guide by William Bigelow], 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-052
  This accession consists of printed materials pertaining to political parties and organizations in South Africa during the apartheid regime. Files are alphabetically listed by topic, organization or title.
  - Afrikaans language monument, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Comittee on Africa (ACOA) [ actions news and printed materials], 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anti-apartheid fliers and statements [by the Coalition Against Apartheid, New Haven], 1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anti-apartheid movement (London), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arekopaneng journal ["we come together", journal of South African Cultural Workers' Association, vol.1, no.3], 1989 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Azania Commando [supplement of Azania Combat, the official organ of Azanian People's Liberation Army], undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - City of Johannesburg [minutes 412 of the city's council], 1964 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Committee on South African War of Resistance (COSAWR), 1988 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ensovoort 'n Tydskrift vir Po ë sie [jg. 1, nr.1], 1981 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Indicator Project South Africa", 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Inside South Africa" [a bimonthly dossier of documents from a challenging South Africa, vol. 1, no. 2], 1990 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - International Conference Against Apartheid Sport [Harare, Zimbabwe), 1987 November 5-7 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Investor Responsibility Research Center, Inc., 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)